<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:41:18 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tabletopflore.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Posts</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 16:47:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wiki</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 22:14:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="welcome-to-flores-worldbuilding-wiki">Welcome to Flore&amp;rsquo;s Worldbuilding Wiki&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Welcome to the wiki for my newer content. My older stuff used to be up on &lt;a href="https://xhoria.miraheze.org/wiki/Main_Page" target="_blank">XhoriaWiki&lt;/a>, but ever since I was able to get my own site working, I felt like moving the newer content over to this site, instead of using the wiki that was originally supposed for just Xhoria.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Ever since I have played Dungeons and Dragons 5th Edition with friends, I have been fascinated by the art of worldbuilding. I&amp;rsquo;ve designed and written about multiple worlds, most of them I personally now deem as insufficient or just kind of mediocre, mostly in comparison to what I am able to envision now.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Xhoria was one of the first worlds I wrote, which quickly got out of hand as I started to write wider and wider, as to creating some depth, leading to a huge backlog that drained my motivation.
I wrote Eden, a short and small world focussed on a central idea, which was fun to explore.
Now I am writing Halcyon, a world where I am primarily focussing on what I find fun in a fantasy world. Exploration, mystery, conflict, drama, etc.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>As I have been able to spend more and more time thinking of my world and fleshing it out, sometimes completely changing fundamental things, I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to have a newfound appreciation for the craft of worldbuilding. It is a form of a creative outlet for myself, and I always find myself thinking of things to add, develop, write, etc. Sometimes these things will never get to see the light of day in a Dungeons and Dragons game, but I still like writing them.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This wiki serves as a source of information for both myself and others interested in my world of Halcyon. I hope to give a sense of wonder and adventure by just reading these articles. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through many stages when writing and designing my worlds.&lt;/em>
&lt;em>I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from primarily focussing on the game to more or less giving more attention to the world, and having the game be a product of the world, not the other way around.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Tarun Johan &amp;ldquo;Flore&amp;rdquo; Lankhaar, November 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="important-pages">Important Pages&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[[Flore&amp;rsquo;s 5e House Rules]]&lt;/li>
&lt;li>[[History of Halcyon]]&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 12:01:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/about/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>