<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wiki on</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/</link><description>Recent content in Wiki on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 22:14:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Halcyon</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/halcyon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/halcyon/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Halcyon&lt;/strong> is a name given to the [[Prime Material Plane]]. It is where most of our adventures take place. It is a world where the lands are broken and scattered over the skies, floating above the open expanse of the [[Great Blue]]. You&amp;rsquo;ll see [[Skyships]] flying over the clouds transporting cargo and people from one city to another, each built on the many floating islands and continents of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is an ancient world, shaped by cataclysmic and ruinous events in history. Old flying cities from before [[the Cataclysm]] now lie ruined in the endless depths of the ocean below and both [[arcane magic|arcane]] and [[divine magic|divine]] artifacts from elder times are scattered across the lands, waiting to be used again&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="naming">Naming&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The name Halcyon became popular among scholars soon after [[the Cataclysm]]. The word itself means a time in the past that is remembered as better than today, characterized by happiness, great success, and prosperity. The [[Sundered Age]] was, to most, a golden age, and after [[The Veiling]], many yearned to return to that idyllic time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="history">History&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="main">&lt;i>Main article: [[History of Halcyon]]&lt;/i>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>From the oldest records of [[Aurora]], it is assumed that the [[Deities]] created our world from the all-encompassing chaos. They created the [[Prime Material Plane]] and its sister [[Multiverse|planes]]. After the world was shaped, the [[Elves]], [[Dwarves]], and [[Humans]] were created by the gods and walked the lands, and after them, others followed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people were given the power of [[Divine Magic]] from the gods to help them protect themselves from their harsh and untamed world, giving rise to the first magic users of the world. Now that people had the power to tame the world on their own, it gave rise to the first sparks of civilization, like the city of [[Aurora]]. The deities also were given a more clear form after religion and worship became more apparent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As time went on, the chaotic cosmos surrounding the planes only continued to grow in rage, culminating in an event called &lt;em>[[The Sundering]]&lt;/em>. This event fundamentally reshaped the world, shattering its essence - it&amp;rsquo;s [[Aether]] - across the spectrum. What was once an enormous stretch of land only surrounded by water, became an uncountable amount of floating islands and continents, all flying high above the unknowable depths of the [[Great Blue]]. In a final attempt to fight back against the unstoppable chaos, [[Luna]] gifted mankind with [[Arcane Magic]], which is the ability for man to create their magic, without having to depend on the [[Deities]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After mankind and the gods were able to push back against the chaos, civilization had to be rebuilt. It also created a schism between the gods, they separated into those that wanted to protect and preserve their children, the [[Prime Deities]], and those that were so torn by grief and loss that they sought to abandon the world and return it to the cosmological chaos, the [[Traitor Gods]]. While only a tenth of the population survived the event, it did eventually usher in a golden age for the world, filled with magical innovation and new technology, pushing mankind to new heights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It did, however, also exemplify the arrogance and selfishness of man. One arcanist challenged the god of death and won, taking his place among the [[Deities]]. Another became so disillusioned with the gods and the world that they lost sight of the meaning and purpose of humanity and the world, vowing to release the [[Traitor Gods]] and use their power to bring ruin and destruction. He succeeded in becoming so powerful to release the [[Traitor Gods]] from their prison realms. They consolidated their power after release and declared war on the [[Prime Deities]] and the world, leading to a chaotic arcane arms race that escalated to a full-on war, later named [[the Cataclysm]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The [[Traitor Gods]] were banished once more to their prison realms during the aftermath of the war. The world was in ruins once more and had to be rebuilt again. The [[Prime Deities]] took another extreme measure to eliminate the chance that anyone would get close to that amount of power and bring about another cataclysmic event. They created the [[Divine Veil]], which barred any god from materializing in the world. They could only influence the world through their most devout followers, leaving the plane to mankind alone. It has now been centuries after [[the Cataclysm]], and the world has begun to create a new history for itself. New nations were formed, and discoveries were made. Who knows what the future will hold for Halcyon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>History of the World</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/history-of-halcyon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/history-of-halcyon/</guid><description>&lt;p>The precise origin of [[Halcyon]] is clouded in mystery. The only sources of information are old relics and ancient ruins and temples throughout the world, some information is gathered directly from the [[Deities|Gods]] themselves, but they speak rarely of the time before man.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-chaos-of-the-cosmos">The Chaos of the Cosmos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the beginning, there was only chaos, a messy cosmological and primordial mayhem that collided and conflicted with itself. It is believed to have been a realm of constant change, anger and hate. This changed when from either beyond the [[cosmos]] or from within it, certain entities used their power and influence of the chaos to stabilize it. These entities were the earliest forms of what we now know as the [[Deities]] of [[Halcyon]]. They carved out a section of the cosmos to begin shaping their vision for a different world. A world that would be known as the [[Prime Material Plane]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chaos surrounding these young entities did not appreciate any sense of order being established within the infinite void. While these two forces fought eachother, it would only be a matter of time before the [[Deities]]&amp;rsquo; world would be consumed by the chaos once more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-creation-of-man">The Creation of Man&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the world began to take its shape, the deities created lesser forms to inhabit their created realm. It is believed that it was [[Titania, The Iridescent Mother|Titania]] who shaped the first beings, the [[Elves]], who would walk upon the new world and gaze up at the heavenly skies as their creators continued to keep the cosmos at bay. Then, [[Mallus, The Forgefather|Mallus]] took it upon himself to forge the [[Dwarves]], with whom he instilled the same desire to tame the world, the desire to &lt;em>create&lt;/em> something. Next was a third race, the [[Humans]], who were instilled with a sense of order by [[Solarion, The Bright King|Solarion]] and curiosity by [[Luna, Mistress of the Moon|Luna]] to bring meaning to the world. Despite their short lives, they were imbued with ambition, joy, and a sense of purpose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the [[Elves]], [[Dwarves]], and [[Humans]], many more species followed. The true origins or creators of these other species were, however, lost to time. Not even the meticulous and comprehensive archives of the ancient city of [[Aurora]] could shine any light upon this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-gift-of-magic">The Gift of Magic&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While the deities were protecting the newly created life on their world from the hostile chaos outside, the creations themselves struggled to survive the harsh and unpredictable environments of an untamed world. They gained knowledge and attempted to build on the land, but even then many lives would be lost because of the seemingly uncaring world. In an attempt to aid their creations, the deities gave them a tiny fragment of their power, a sliver of the creation magic that brought mankind to the realm in the first place, to protect and shape the world around them as they deemed appropriate. This was the earliest form of [[Divine Magic]]. A type of magic that connected the people with their creators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As time went on, more of what we now deem as normal came into existence. [[Solarion, The Bright King|Solarion]] and [[Luna, Mistress of the Moon|Luna]] gave a sense of rhythm to the world by having the star shine its light upon the lands for half of the day, while the two moons, [[Majora]] and [[Minora]], kept a watchful eye during nightfall.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-city-of-aurora">The City of [[Aurora]]&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The first spark of civilization was [[Aurora]], the oldest surviving city in [[Halcyon]], where community and preservation grew important as the world around them was still harsh to its people. The city housed a tightly knit community that lived in peace and harmony despite the brutal outside. The city would have the earliest known temples to the deities, and the oldest known records of history. These records are widely regarded as the primary source of understanding of the creation of our world. While there are various regional differences in the historical record, the broad strokes of this mythic history are undeniable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was in this city that mankind began to worship the deities, and it was only then that they were given name and form. The deities that we know now might have been significantly changed through this worship, but it is assumed that even before our world existed, the deities&amp;rsquo; thoughts and emotions were still unique to them, but only reinforced through worship.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-sundering">[[The Sundering]]&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As mankind and the deities together poured their heart and soul into their realm, the chaos of the cosmos surrounding it only grew in anger and rage. It was only when the heavens began to fall and the essence of the world itself began to reclaim what was theirs, that mankind became aware of the wrath that outside forces were capable of. This event in history is called &lt;em>the Sundering&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Primal beings spewed forth from the earth and the seas and entities from beyond the heavens came down to destroy everything. This fight between the deities and the chaos fundamentally reshaped the land of [[Halcyon]], shattering its essence, also known as [[Aether]], across the spectrum. What was once an enormous stretch of land only surrounded by water, became an uncountable amount of floating islands and continents, all flying high above the unknowable depths of the [[Great Blue]] being held up by immense amounts of [[Aether]].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-gift-of-the-arcane">The Gift of the Arcane&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As the deities became desperate to save their realm and mankind was suffering greatly, the deities resorted to the most extreme measures. [[Luna, Mistress of the Moon|Luna]] gifted mankind with the ability to create magic on their own, without having to borrow the creation magic from the deities. This made mankind more independent from their creators and gave them more power over the world. The people that had a potency for this new kind of magic called themselves [[Arcanists]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This gave both the deities and mankind enough power to subdue the chaos attacking them, bringing forth an end to [[The Sundering]].&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="aftermath-of-the-sundering">Aftermath of the Sundering&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Only a tenth of the population survived, and it created a schism within the [[Deities]]. Some of them wanted to protect the world with all of their power, some of them were overcome by grief and wanted to return the world to the cosmological chaos, as it was deemed a failure to them and too much to bear. This divide in the gods eventually culminated in the imprisonment of those that sought to bring the world to chaos. They were imprisoned in planes adjacent to the [[Prime Material Plane]], where they would be unable to influence the world. Those that sought to protect their creation became the [[Prime Deities]] of [[Halcyon]], while the others became known as the [[Traitor Gods]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the realm was now scattered and broken, most of the civilized world had to be rebuilt. [[Aurora]], stood the strongest, and even now is the only known continent that is still rooted in the [[Great Blue]]. The [[Elves]] that primarily inhabited it brought it back to its original glory. The [[Dwarves]], [[Gnomes]], and [[Humans]] that lived in [[Aurora]] invented technology and magic that was able to use the latent magical essence in the world, which was used in [[Skyship]] technology. A combination of using [[Arcane Magic]] and the natural [[Aether]] of the world to transport yourself through the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="golden-age-of-halcyon">Golden age of Halcyon&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Together with this new technology and the gift of the [[Arcane Magic|arcane]], mankind sought to tame and master the new world in front of them, culminating in a golden age of the world. It opened up many possibilities for everyone to harness the world, magic, and its secrets. It is widely known as a long period of technological and magical progress for mankind, where magic users were able to innovate in unprecedented ways, completing difficult tasks with ease. It spawned wondrous, but also dangerous, new forms of life and power in the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-cataclysm">[[The Cataclysm]]&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>But this progress also spread a deep rot through the world. It exemplified the arrogance and selfishness of mankind. One arcanist was obsessed with becoming a god, and became so powerful that they were able to challenge the deity of death, and won, taking their place among the gods. They subsequently made sure no one could gain that amount of power ever again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Others became so disillusioned with the gods that they thought themselves to be the true owners of the world. Some of them went even further, losing sight of the meaning and purpose the world of [[Halcyon]] had to them, aligning themselves with the [[Traitor Gods]], vowing to release them to give the world back to the [[cosmos]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One such powerful arcanist, [[Cyrus Tarathis]], together with a group of other arcanists, indulged in this nihilistic worldview and sought power from the imprisoned gods, succeeding in opening the gates of their prisons. The [[Traitor Gods]] warped their prisons into reflections of their corruption, and their prisons also warped them in diabolical and terrible ways. Their emotions of loss and grief from &lt;em>[[the Sundering]]&lt;/em> were twisted into hatred and an urge to dominate and ruin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These newly released gods brought the arcanist under their wing and consolidated their power in secret. After a while, they declared war upon [[Halcyon]] and the [[Prime Deities]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This chaotic war over the future of the realm became known as &lt;em>[[The Cataclysm]]&lt;/em>. Not much is known about the battles that ensued during this crucial event in time, but it&amp;rsquo;s effects are felt throughout the world. Ruins and artifacts from the war tell of unknown battles and stories. Legends and stories are told about the figures that fought in this war. It&amp;rsquo;s speculated that only a fifth of the world population survived this event. For the most part, all traces of the old world were erased from the face of [[Halcyon]], leaving only a few ancient civilizations in well-preserved ruins.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-veiling">[[The Veiling]]&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The victorious [[Prime Deities]] banished their betraying kin back to their respective prison realms, and the world had to recover once more, just as it had to after the [[The Sundering]]. However, the threat that anyone could be convinced to bring about a second Cataclysm, still existed. The [[Deities|Gods]] created the [[Divine Veil]], barring any god from materializing in the world, even themselves, and they could only influence the world through their most devout followers. This left mankind to survive on its own, to rebuild civilization, ushering in a new age of man.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="age-of-man">Age of Man&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After the veiling of the world, each different portion of the world began its own history. Some turned towards the [[Prime Deities]], some turned to the [[Arcane Magic|arcane]], but every single culture started a new history.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Metaknowledge</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/metaknowledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 18:49:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/metaknowledge/</guid><description>&lt;p>This wiki is meant for you to get a deeper understanding of the world of [[Halcyon]], however it is important to mention that you should separate the knowledge you as a player gain from this wiki, and the knowledge your character has. As much as I highly appreciate someone digging deeper into this world of my making, please make sure to keep player knowledge and character knowledge seperate. When in doubt, you can always ask me about it, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The wiki will &lt;strong>never&lt;/strong> contain spoilers for any campaign or character backstory. It will only contain information to immerse yourself in the history of the setting and its people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Thank you for reading this page, I appreciate it.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flore's 5e House Rules</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/flores-5e-house-rules/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 15:38:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/wiki/flores-5e-house-rules/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article explains some of the homebrew rules, variant rules, and other important things to mention about how I personally run my Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons 5th Edition games.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="alternative-resurrection-rules">Alternative Resurrection Rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I use Matthew Mercer&amp;rsquo;s rules for resurrection, which is explained below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Character death can often prove to become a minor inconvenience in some campaigns once the adventuring party reaches a certain level, with spells being available to return fallen comrades from the afterlife with temporary setbacks, robbing a small element of danger and threat to future conflicts and challenges within the story. If you wish to elevate the gravity of character death, you can introduce this optional rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a character is dead, and a resurrection is attempted by a spell or spell effect with longer than a 1 action casting time, a Resurrection Challenge is initiated. Up to 3 members of the adventuring party can offer to contribute to the ritual via a Contribution Skill Check. The DM asks them each to make a skill check based on their form of contribution, with the DC of the check adjusting to how helpful/impactful the DM feels the contribution would be. For example, praying to the deity of the devout, fallen character may require an Intelligence (Religion) check at an easy to medium difficulty, where loudly demanding the soul of the fallen to return from the aether may require a Charisma (Intimidation) check at a very hard or nearly impossible difficulty. Advantage and disadvantage can apply here based on how perfect, or off base, the contribution offered is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After all contributions are completed, the DM then rolls a single, final Resurrection success check with no modifier. The base DC for the final resurrection check is 10, increasing by 1 for each previous successful resurrection the character has undergone (signifying the slow erosion of the soul’s connection to this world). For each successful contribution skill check, this DC is decreased by 3, whereas each failed contribution skill check increases the DC by 1. Upon a successful resurrection check, the player’s soul (should it be willing) will be returned to the body, and the ritual succeeded. On a failed check, the soul does not return and the character is lost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only the strongest of magical incantations can bypass this resurrection challenge, in the form of the True Resurrection or Wish spells. These spells can also restore a character to life who was lost due to a failed resurrection ritual.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a spell with a casting time of 1 action is used to attempt to restore life (via the Revivify spell or similar effects), no contribution skill checks are allowed. The character casting the spell makes a Rapid Resurrection check, rolling a d20 and adding their spellcasting ability modifier. The DC is 10, increasing by 1 for each previous successful resurrection the character has undergone. On a failure, the character’s soul is not lost, but the resurrection fails and increases any future Resurrection checks’ DC by 1. No further attempts can be made to restore this character to life until a resurrection spell with a casting time higher than 1 action is attempted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="banned-races">Banned Races&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are a few races that are either overpowered or do not fit within the world of [[Halcyon]]. These are as follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Aarakocra&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simic Hybrid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vedalken&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Variant Human (Given that I&amp;rsquo;m planning on giving everyone a free feat)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bloodied-condition">Bloodied Condition&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A character is bloodied when the character&amp;rsquo;s hit points are equal to or less then one-half the character&amp;rsquo;s maximum hit points, rounded down. One-half the character&amp;rsquo;s maximum hit points is referred to as the character&amp;rsquo;s bloodied value. For example: a character with 50 maximum hit points has a bloodied value of 25, and is bloodied whenever the character&amp;rsquo;s hit points are equal to or less than 25. Most of the time this will be used to communicate progress into defeating a monster and will have no impact on gameplay. Some monsters or homebrew classes might have features that activate whenever a character has the bloodied condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bonus-action-healing-potions">Bonus Action Healing Potions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Using any healing potion on yourself will cost a bonus action instead of an action. Using any healing potion on someone else will still cost an action.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="carrying-capacity">Carrying Capacity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If it makes sense for you to carry a thing, you can carry it. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to carry whole statues, but I do not mind you having a lot of tiny stuff in your inventory. The exception to this is when it&amp;rsquo;s in huge quantities, think a gigantic hoard of gold, or a pile of swords and armor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="intense-critical-hits">Intense Critical Hits&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you roll a 20 on your attack roll against a creature, instead of either rolling twice the dice or double the amount, you add the maximum amount your dice could roll to your damage. Example: Your attack does 2d6+3 damage, on a crit you add 12 to that roll, which is the maximum of 2d6.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="variant-rules">Variant Rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="feats">Feats&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I allow feats. I think it adds a lot of customizability to the game and your character. I&amp;rsquo;m also allowing one single free feat for everyone at level 1. This rule might change.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="inspiration">Inspiration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried using inspiration in a game yet, and probably still wont. If I ever decide to use inspiration I will let you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="level-advancement-without-xp">Level Advancement Without XP&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t like using XP for leveling because it encourages combat over the other pillars of Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons, exploration and social interaction. I, as the DM, decide when the party levels up. This is decided on the amount of adventures and quests the party has completed and their difficulty. All members of the party are the same level&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="more-difficult-identification">More difficult Identification&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I like magic items to be a bit more special than normal. You can identify a magic item using the &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Identify&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; spell as usual, but you can only identify a magic item during a short rest if you succeed on an Intelligence (Arcana) check with a DC determined by the rarity of the magic item.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="multiclassing">Multiclassing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I also allow multiclassing, at least if you know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>