<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>elysium on Flore's Insignificant Thoughts</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/tags/elysium/</link><description>Flore's Insignificant Thoughts (elysium)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>drmoonlington@gmail.com (Flore)</managingEditor><webMaster>drmoonlington@gmail.com (Flore)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tabletopflore.com/tags/elysium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pantheon of Elysium: More Deities, Story, and Culture</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-elysium-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>drmoonlington@gmail.com (Flore)</author><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-elysium-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, last post was quite a long one. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a great start to my pantheon already. This article will flesh out the pantheon more by adding minor deities to fill some domains, add the &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eMgPgbRb_fA">one good story&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;, and develop how the culture and actual religion in this world would be like.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="even-more-deities">Even More Deities&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I looked at my current set of five deities and what domains they represent for clerics, and found out that we&amp;rsquo;re basically covering all of them (some even twice), besides Death, Grave, and Peace. There are also aspects of the world that I&amp;rsquo;d want represented as a deity, like the sky, water, angels, and probably more that I haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned before. I think the best way to implement these minor deities is to have them act as underlings or servants to the five core deities. For example: I feel like a couple of smaller deities of elements like air, fire, stone, and water fit well underneath Rosaria. A deity of angels would fit under Solana. Likewise, the deity of death and the afterlife could fit neatly beneath Kairos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I want these deities to have their own little corner of the pantheon for themselves. They shouldn&amp;rsquo;t make the Pantheon seem bloated and complex. They should be extra options for clerics and paladins to choose from, while the core five are what I will primarily focus on. I might even steal some deities from my old world, since some minor used ones were quite good on paper. Because I want to make it as simple as possible, I will limit myself to only a maximum of around 3 underlings per core deity, and a minimum of 1. The minimum is in place to make sure every deity has at least one underling. It would feel weird for some to have many while others have none.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-minor-deities">The Minor Deities&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The deities Aeril, Scylla, Pyrus, and Titanos are the four minor deities of Air, Water, Fire, and Earth, respectively. They were brought to divinity by Rosaria after she became a deity herself. These four deities keep the elemental chaos in check and are often the patron deities of the elementally aligned, like the genasi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charos will be the minor deity of the afterlife, while Daemos will be the minor deity of death. The afterlife and death itself are usually quite the mystery, which is why they will be beneath Kairos. With Kairos also being the god of Fate, it would make sense that death and the afterlife would be under his domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sinemo, the minor goddess of Music and Art, and Thena, the minor goddess of Emotion, Compassion, and Grief, will join Veles. I think art in general fits with the domain of Veles quite nicely, while the domain of emotion fits well with the theme of family and civilization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seranah will be the minor goddess of Angels. She would fall under Solana. Angels are most often associated with light and heaven and whatnot, so it would make sense that Solana would be the one to have her under her wing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think Bahamut, minor deity of dragons, would actually fit really well under Lunola. Dragons are, in my opinion, magical creatures in and of themselves. I love dragons in Dungeons and Dragons and will always use them when possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="some-thoughts">Some Thoughts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty content with what I have now. I have five core deities that I want to focus most of my attention on, while also having a couple of extra deities that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to flesh out immediately that fill in some space. The total amount of deities is now at 15, which I think is a solid amount. It definitely should not become any more than that. I had the thought that some of these deities, just by their domain, should be powerful themselves. Like, why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t Daemos, the god of death, not be a core deity? But, adding the &amp;lsquo;minor&amp;rsquo; to his title, makes it a non-issue, in my opinion. I&amp;rsquo;m not one to decide on &amp;lsquo;god power levels&amp;rsquo;, but I feel that these minor deities mostly get their power from their respective core deity. &lt;em>They&lt;/em> have control over these domains, but choose to delegate it to others. Insert workplace comparison here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-one-good-story">The One Good Story&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So, here&amp;rsquo;s my attempt at making a sort of creation myth for the world that attempts to incorporate the &amp;lsquo;one good story&amp;rsquo; Dael Kingsmill talked about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Long ago, nothing existed. Only Aleph existed. Aleph created the world of Elysium. A simple world. Aleph created the Wishgranter, a small building on the world which would grant anyone a wish, if they faced its challenges. The first to make a wish were two sisters. One saw the power in the physical power of mankind, while the other was fascinated by the secrets of the world. Then came a woman that accepted the wilderness for what it is and forgave it for what it could do. After her, a man made a wish. He was a father who valued family and community. The last to make a wish was a man who came alone.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Long after their deaths, Aleph granted them divinity. They became gods of their own personal convictions. This also amplified their convictions, which created conflict. Aleph also granted a few other beings divinity after their wish came true. The deities made changes to the world, influencing people and making them more aligned with their ideals. Once each deity planted their own seed of conviction, Aleph barred the deities from Elysium, including himself. They were no longer able to influence the world in major ways. Some were furious, some were fine with it. Aleph then went into an eternal slumber.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="more-thoughts">More Thoughts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now, you might say: “Flore, where&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;lsquo;Authority&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Harbor&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Purpose&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;Treachery?'” and to that I would reply: “Yeah, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really able to put that in there.” I think that if you&amp;rsquo;re working out a good simple pantheon from the ground up, this would be a great way to get some core ideas implemented. The problem is that I&amp;rsquo;ve already created my pantheon, and they already represent their own thing. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m generally bad at writing creation myths, but that&amp;rsquo;s another thing. I think this works well enough as a creation story and gives you some idea about how these deities came to be. I&amp;rsquo;m intentionally keeping things vague because this might be an aspect that I want to explore in the game.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-bit-of-culture-and-religion">A bit of Culture and Religion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this section, I want to explore some religious practices for Elysium. I still want to keep it simple and easy to understand, not just for myself, but also for my players. I was thinking of keeping it to maybe some commandments (think of paladin tenets). Chances are I might steal most commandments from deities already existing in D&amp;amp;D, since &amp;lsquo;commandment writing&amp;rsquo; is not my strongsuit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="solana-the-bright-queen">Solana, the Bright Queen&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>She represents justice, valor, and retribution. Solana is a deity that represents law and vengeance, so I think she would encourage her followers to follow the laws set by leadership and also those set by yourself. She would also encourage fighting with the strength you have, be brave, and to defend the weak. I think a lot of her commandments mirror that of the paladin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Oath of Vengeance&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her commandments would be something like: - Defend the weak, persecute those that are guilty, and protect the ideals of justice and might. - Bravery above all. There is no glory in cowardice. - Be ever vigilant for evil. People are quick to forget the lessons of the past.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="lunola-the-lady-of-magic">Lunola, the Lady of Magic&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>She represents discovery, magic, and knowledge. She would definitely encourage finding out the truth in everything, to leave no secrets untouched. Lunola is also the goddess of magic, so expanding your knowledge into the arcane in any way, shape, or form would be encouraged. Not only that, but she also encourages people to forge their own path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her commandments would be: - Seize your own destiny by pursuing your passions. - Follow the echoes of lost magics, forgotten sites, and ancient art, for within these lie the deepest of Elysium&amp;rsquo;s secrets. - Unmask those who would defy Lunola. Learn their secrets and unveil them to the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rosaria-the-red-maiden">Rosaria, the Red Maiden&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>She represents the wilderness, love, and forgiveness, so she would encourage protecting the untamed wilderness from exploitation. Rosaria would also always prefer forgiveness to vengeance. Having mercy and patience is important to her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her commandments are: - Protect the untamed wilderness from exploitation and destruction. - Lead with mercy, patience, and compassion. Inspire others to unite in fellowship. - Embrace and respect the savage nature of the world. Exist in harmony with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="veles-the-great-creator">Veles, the Great Creator&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Veles is the god of creation, invention, family, and civilization, so upholding the values of family would be a big thing for him. He also encourages everyone to continue innovating and creating new things, not just physical, but cultural as well. He also encourages teamwork and working together with everyone, for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His commandments would be: - Uphold and revere the spirit of invention. Create new settlements, build where inspiration strikes, and expand the edicts of the Law Bearer. - Uphold and promote loyalty to your family, loyalty to your clan, and loyalty to your people. - Utilize the company and aid of others. The efforts of the individual often pale against the capabilities of the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="kairos-the-mysterious">Kairos, the Mysterious&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kairos is a god of secrets, shadows, and mystery. He also represents individualism as a theme, so working alone is a big part of his encouragement. He also encourages people to live free, but keep secrets. After all, secrets are what are interesting about a person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His commandments are: - Walk unbridled and untethered, forging new memories and experiences. - Learn all you can, and keep hidden that which you know. Reveal what pieces you must, but never the whole. - Seek and exalt places where no light touches.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These three articles were a lot of fun to write. It might not be a lot of details written down for each deity, but that&amp;rsquo;s not always necessary. I can always create when needed to. Like I said in my first article about pantheons and religion: Its always best to conserve your creative energy for when you need it, instead of expending it all on things you wont use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides that, did I do everything I wanted to do? No, there were things I would rather have expanded upon more, but then again, I&amp;rsquo;ll do that when inspiration strikes me, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to force myself to create. Overall, I think this is a great start to my worldbuilding in Elysium, and I will continue to expand upon the different facets of that world another time. I feel like the Magic: The Gathering system of the five conflicts really work well. It brings a lot more interest to not only the deities themselves, but what the denizens of your world believe in and uphold. As much as I like Dael Kingsmill&amp;rsquo;s system, it clashes with what I already have envisioned, but still works really well on its own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no idea what my next article is going to be, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see when that comes up. Again, I appreciate every bit of feedback, and I would love to hear your thoughts about this miniseries about religion and pantheons. &amp;lsquo;Til the next article!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pantheon of Elysium</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-elysium-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>drmoonlington@gmail.com (Flore)</author><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-elysium-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like I said in my last article, this article is going to be me trying to take the (arguably small amount of) knowledge I gained from writing that article and apply that to my new world of &lt;em>Elysium&lt;/em>. I want to see what kind of system I want to use and what I want to focus on, and maybe work out some cultures and religions as well. As not everyone knows what Elysium is, I&amp;rsquo;ll start by giving a small introduction to the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="quick-intro-to-elysium">Quick intro to Elysium&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Elysium is a world filled with wonder and fantasy. The world itself is an enormous expanse of ocean, with floating islands in the sky. Skyships are flying over the clouds, going from enormous floating cities to smaller villages on those floating islands. There are ruined civilizations that are either still floating through corrupted and dangerous clouds or have fallen and now lie at the bottom of the ocean.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="wishgranter">Wishgranter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The most interesting thing in Elysium is the &lt;em>Wishgranter&lt;/em>, a colossal building floating above the ocean. It&amp;rsquo;s an extremely challenging dungeon, but grants a wish at the end of it all. The Wishgranter has shaped the world to the way it is through many wishes. Every time someone makes a wish, the building grows larger, teleports away, and returns to a different place a few decades later.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="factions-and-politics">Factions and Politics&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Many nations in Elysium want the power of the Wishgranter for themselves, which is why the return of the Wishgranter usually is a spark for war. Each nation and faction that inhabit these skylands have their wishes they want to fulfill, some for selfish reasons, some for the betterment of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-view">My View&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My vision for Elysium is a world that can house many differing campaigns. It could be a political campaign with intrigue and subterfuge. Perhaps it can house a campaign with a lot of exploration, finding the secrets of the world and its ancient civilizations. It could also focus on the Wishgranter itself, which could lead to a very dungeon-heavy campaign. Not only that, but it can also be a mix of these types. With my last world of &lt;em>Eden&lt;/em> being very dark and gloomy, I felt like I wanted to make something more fantasy, with some twists.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="designing-the-pantheon">Designing The Pantheon&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that I’ve explained a bit of what this world is about: Religions and the Pantheon. I’m going to be using multiple sources to maybe steal from or take inspiration from. I’ll note those when they come up. Furthermore, I’m also writing this article at the same time as creating the pantheon, so if it feels a little like rambling, bear with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-system">The System&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As I have explained in the last article, I’m not a big fan of the Loose Pantheon, and I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling like I should go for a duality or a monotheistic world here. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to actually go with a loose pantheon. While I was writing this, I initially wrote a that I wanted to create a tight pantheon. Now that I have finished some aspects of the pantheon though, it looks more and more like a loose pantheon. I&amp;rsquo;ll have a couple of core deities and a few lesser gods to fill the space. I came across this &lt;a href="https://theangrygm.com/conflicted-beliefs/">great article by the Angry DM&lt;/a> using Magic: The Gathering&amp;rsquo;s system of 5 colors that contrast with each other in such a way that have 2 allies and 2 enemies each, creating a sort of balance that is hard to disturb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is also this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eMgPgbRb_fA">great video by Dael Kingsmill&lt;/a> about how she would design a pantheon, which has some interesting insight into where to start with your pantheon. She recommends thinking of four character archetypes in your &amp;lsquo;one good story&amp;rsquo;: Authority, Harbor, Purpose, and Treachery. Highly recommend looking into those two sources. What I&amp;rsquo;m currently thinking of is 5 deities that were made by one overgod-like entity, plus maybe a few lesser deities to fill out the space (if there is any.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="theme-conflicts">Theme Conflicts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A core part of what the Angry DM described is having 5 different theme conflicts and using those to create your deities. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to start with thinking of those. Two nations I already designed a little before writing this article are the nations of &lt;em>Solari and Lunari&lt;/em>. The Solari Diarchy is a very authoritarian kingdom ruled by a King and Queen, while a council of mages rules the Lunari Dominion. There&amp;rsquo;s some sort of conflict here, like might vs. magic. They don&amp;rsquo;t oppose each other &lt;em>that&lt;/em> much, but it&amp;rsquo;s something of a start. The theme of might is also about believing in the strength, leadership, and power of yourself or your nation. It also includes perseverance through any obstacle. Magic on the other hand also includes mystery, knowledge, and wisdom, to some extent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another nation I designed before writing this article was the nation of Lyonett, of which the capital is an enormous flying airship. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>the&lt;/em> nation for technological advances and research. Now, I wanted this conflict to be tradition vs. progress, with Lyonett embodying progress, but the conflict didn&amp;rsquo;t really work when I had to think about tradition. It&amp;rsquo;s not particularly a conflict I want to explore within my world, even if it is an interesting conflict in general. I think a conflict that would work here is individualism vs. collectivism. Should each person live for themselves unfettered, or is it better to cooperate and compromise? I envision the people and engineers of Lyonett as selfless people. They research technology and innovate not just for themselves, but for the betterment of everyone around them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A conflict I think could be interesting to explore is retribution vs. forgiveness. Which is the true nature of justice or the purpose of the law? Vengeance is not always the right choice, but neither is forgiveness. Which side a character might take can give you a lot of information about that character&amp;rsquo;s ideals and worldview. Why they take their stance is also interesting to think about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted to also add some sort of law vs. chaos conflict, but I found that to be too direct. I think civilization vs. wilderness is a better representation of what I would find interesting to explore in my world. Wilderness also does not have the negative connotation chaos does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now for less of a philosophical conflict and more one I&amp;rsquo;d love to add: discovery vs. mystery. Part of Dungeons and Dragons is, of course, exploration. The theme of discovery is largely present in it. The world is unexplored and holds many secrets, why not seek those out? On the other hand, there are things that are legend or myth for a reason, the things that should not be explored. The secrets you do not want exposed, either personal or on a worldly scale. Keeping those safe is just as important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll play with these five conflicts: — Might vs. Magic — Individualism vs. Collectivism — Retribution vs. Forgiveness — Civilization vs. Wilderness — Discovery vs. Mystery&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-pantheon-itself">The Pantheon Itself&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that I have my conflicts, It is time to put them together in a way that sort of makes sense. I first thought of the Solari Diarchy and thought that Might and Retribution is a good combination for that nation, and thus their deity. A deity of war, of strength, of justice, and vengeance. It sort of summarizes the Diarchy in a way. They want retribution for what happened to them when the Solari and the Lunari split in two, believing in the strength of man to bring them forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, the Lunari believe in Magic and Discovery. They chose to split off from the Lunari some time ago, focusing on their intelligence and magic to keep them safe. This will then be my second deity, a deity of knowledge, of magic, and of discovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next combination and deity I want to make is the deity of Wilderness and Forgiveness. A deity of nature, of love, of the animals and the weather, of letting go and forgiving. Perhaps it is one of the more self-evident combinations, but it gives more character than a generic nature deity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my friends over in the Lyonett, I think Collectivism and Civilization make a great combination. A deity of creation, of tinkering, of working together for a greater good. It exemplifies the ideals of the Lyonett.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last combination that is left over is Individualism and Mystery. A deity of secrets, of legends, of myths, and of shadow. On face value, it might seem as the only deity that you could consider as &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo;. Something to think about.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-actual-gods">The Actual Gods&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Solana, the Bright Queen, is the Goddess of Light, Justice, and War. She will represent might and retribution as themes. She is a pillar of justice and honor and is often symbolized by the bright sun in the sky. Generals in the military might align with Solana, and so might those that are not magically aligned as well. Believing in the strength that is inside you and never giving up are the most important commandments she has. A cleric worshiping Solana might take the Light, Order, or War domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lunola, the Lady of Magic, is the Goddess of Magic, Discovery, and Knowledge. She represents magic and discovery as themes. She clashes with Solana as she believes that knowledge and magic are what make people strong. All the magic in Elysium is possible of course thanks to Lunola. She encourages everyone to forge their path in history, and to choose, not be victim to fate. She is often symbolized by the moon in the sky at night, as it changes its phases and is opposite of the Sun. (Usually.) A cleric worshiping Lunola might take the Arcana, Knowledge, or Twilight domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rosaria, the Red Maiden, is the Goddess of the Wild, Love, and Nature. She represents wilderness and forgiveness. Symbolized by the red rose, she is beautiful and fragile, yet its thorns cannot be ignored. Her domain is the nature and weather of Elysium, which is often beautiful but can be dangerous. Kind of like love. (Sorta.) She clashes with Solana as she believes that forgiveness and acceptance is the true way of living and that revenge only breeds hatred. Rosaria believes that leaving the world untouched and letting the wilderness do its thing is better than shaping it to mankind&amp;rsquo;s needs. Live together with nature, not sacrifice it for your own good. A cleric worshiping Rosaria might take the Nature, Life, or Tempest domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Veles, the Great Creator, is the God of Creation, Family, and Progress. Representing collectivism and civilization, he encourages creativity and innovation in people, not just for technology or magic, but also for culture and their traditions. He allies himself with Lunola in some ways that he wishes for Elysium&amp;rsquo;s denizens to continue moving forward. Veles clashes with Rosaria in that Veles sees mankind&amp;rsquo;s work on the land as commendable. It&amp;rsquo;s taking what is there and making it better for everyone. He is often symbolized by a gear. A cleric that worships Veles might take the Forge or Order domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kairos, the Mysterious, is the God of Secrets, Shadows, Mystery, and of Fate. He represents individualism and mystery. Symbolized by the four-pointed star, he represents all that is unknown in the world. The things people don&amp;rsquo;t see, don&amp;rsquo;t hear, and don&amp;rsquo;t speak of. Lunola is often infatuated by the idea of uncovering the secrets Kairos holds. All the while, he encourages people to think for themselves, and keep the secrets they hold so dearly. The world is a dangerous place, you know? While Veles encourages everyone to work together, Kairos knows this only leads to compromise and not the &lt;em>ideal&lt;/em> outcome. A cleric worshiping Kairos might take the Knowledge or Trickery domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aleph, the Overgod, is the God of Gods. He created Elysium and its denizens. He also gave power to these five gods. After his work was done, he went into an eternal sleep. He isn&amp;rsquo;t worshiped outright, but his influence still emanates throughout the world. He is symbolized by a singular closed eye.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="my-thoughts-so-far">My Thoughts So Far&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I think I have a strong start here. The deities conflicting with each other like this creates interesting story opportunities right from the get go. I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with Solana, Lunola, and Rosaria, mostly because I wrote them first and had a good idea for them from the start. Veles is an interesting addition, but I think it works quite well. I originally had two different conflicts: tradition vs. progress and free will vs. fate, but I felt the combination of tradition and fate didn&amp;rsquo;t give me much to work with. Eventually I scrapped that idea and I ended up with what I have now. If I&amp;rsquo;m looking at the cleric subclasses, I am actually missing a couple of domains. I will add a couple smaller, lesser deities to embody some specific aspects of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article has been going on for way too long now, so I&amp;rsquo;ll continue this in a second part later. In that part, I&amp;rsquo;ll create a sort of origin story for the deities and talk about the actual religion around these five deities. I&amp;rsquo;ll also add some lesser deities to the pantheon. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your thoughts so far! &amp;lsquo;Til the next article!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pantheons and Religions</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheons-and-religions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>drmoonlington@gmail.com (Flore)</author><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheons-and-religions/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the first article on this blog of mine, I wanted to discuss the role that the deities, religions, and pantheons in your world plays, both in worldbuilding and your tabletop games. I&amp;rsquo;m now figuring out the deities for my world of &lt;em>Elysium&lt;/em>, and I wanted to share my thoughts about designing them in this article.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="worldbuilding-deities">Worldbuilding Deities&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Personally, I use deities and pantheons because I really have to, most TTRPGs kind of expects you to have them in your world. They&amp;rsquo;re a great way to explain the creation myth of your world and exemplify some aspects of your world by making the most forefront deities inhibit those aspects. An example of this in my pantheons would be the deity &lt;em>Lumen&lt;/em> in my abandoned world of &lt;em>Xhoria&lt;/em>. He personified light, order, law, and the sun. Xhoria was a world split between law and chaos, or at least, that&amp;rsquo;s what it was supposed to be. (I abandoned it for a reason.) Many of the civilized nations worshiped Lumen because he personified order and law, in the hope that he would bring stability to the nation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the main choices you make when designing deities is their involvement in the world. Do they answer the call of prayer often, or are they absent from the world? &lt;em>Do they even exist?&lt;/em> (Hey, that&amp;rsquo;s an option as well.) I like the idea of them being not too benevolent, but also not too absent either. The middle ground seems to be fine for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="different-systems">Different Systems&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s also the distinction between what kind of religious system you want to apply to your world. There are a couple of systems in the DMG, like the Loose Pantheon, which according to the book is: &amp;ldquo;A multitude of deities rule the various aspects of existence, variously cooperating with and competing against one another to administer the affairs of the universe.&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t like this type, seems like a lot of work that isn&amp;rsquo;t really relevant to what I need and want for my games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In contrast to the Loose Pantheon, there&amp;rsquo;s also the Tight Pantheon, which &amp;ldquo;focuses on a single religion whose teachings and edicts embrace a small group of deities.&amp;rdquo; I like this one more than the loose one, since it has a lot more structure, while you still can have the inter-deity squabbles you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also the monotheistic and dualism systems, meaning one or two deities respectively. Monotheism always felt a bit… boring to me, personally. Especially in a fantasy setting. Dualism is a lot more interesting, since it has an inherent conflict, which creates drama. Drama is inevitably what I want in my stories and worlds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="religions">Religions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So when it comes to religions and their ceremonies and rituals, I do not have much experience with that. The designated behaviors and practices, morals, beliefs, and worldviews that are attached to a religion, have always been fairly simple in my worlds. For this, I highly recommend watching &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ml88aKmJyVM">Matthew Colville&amp;rsquo;s series&lt;/a> on creating a Pantheon, Religion, and a culture surrounding it. He explains it much better than I could.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the main takeaway from this is to shape your own deities and religious systems to what you think is relevant to the story or world you want to make, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really the best kind of advice since that&amp;rsquo;s kind of what you&amp;rsquo;re doing with most of your worldbuilding anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="their-use-in-ttrpgs">Their use in TTRPGs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My experience with TTRPGs is not awfully long, only around 4 years of playing (as of the day that I&amp;rsquo;m writing this), but I&amp;rsquo;ve played D&amp;amp;D5e, had a thorough look at Pathfinder 2e, and dabbled a bit in SWADE. In D&amp;amp;D and in Pathfinder, it&amp;rsquo;s automatically assumed that gods exist and exert influence. Obviously, divine magic has to come from &lt;em>somewhere&lt;/em>. Now, I love clerics, they&amp;rsquo;re probably my favorite class to play in D&amp;amp;D because of the amount of options they have in and outside of combat. Clerics (and sometimes Paladins) get their powers from the deities, posing as conduits for their god&amp;rsquo;s power and will. I love it if non-clerics also are religious in some aspect, since it can actually give a quick glance into the personality of a character through what deity they worship or at least associate loosely with.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="adventures-and-stories">Adventures and Stories&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I think in most games deities only really come up in medium to high level story arcs, helping the gods beat up an evil god, stopping a very evil god from resurrecting due to a large cult of some kind, stories like that. In lower level situations, you will probably deal more with the people that serve the bad gods than the gods themselves. They&amp;rsquo;re definitely a good source for story and adventure ideas for your players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pantheons, gods and religions are very deeply engrained in most fantasy TTRPGs, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of expected. They&amp;rsquo;re a great source of adventure ideas and stories as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-attempts-at-pantheons">My Attempts at Pantheons&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So I&amp;rsquo;ve had two different worlds with pantheons, working on a third. One has a lot (and I mean a lot) of deities, and one only has two.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="xhoria">Xhoria&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A lot of my time building Xhoria has been, arguably, wasted on its deities. It contained 100+ deities over multiple pantheons&amp;hellip; of which only a group of twelve were relevant, while taking a lot of my creative energy. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the main reasons I abandoned that world, but I&amp;rsquo;ll write a longer article about that some other day. You can read more about a couple of them on &lt;a href="https://xhoria.miraheze.org/wiki/Pantheons_of_Xhoria">my wiki&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="eden">Eden&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Eden has an interesting system of only two &lt;em>assumed&lt;/em> deities, Lux and Nox, who are both not very friendly towards mankind. They&amp;rsquo;re both responsible for the two big troubles of the City of Lights. Clerics in Eden believe in the domains and not the gods, and get their divine magic from their conviction and dedication to that domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Very big spoilers below for my players who play in Eden, or if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to know.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="spoiler">So, between you and me, Lux and Nox do not exist, powerful forces do inhabit the world, like &lt;em>His Radiance&lt;/em> and the &lt;em>Twelve Knights of Radiance&lt;/em>, but they&amp;rsquo;re not considered &lt;em>deities&lt;/em>. Lux and Nox aren&amp;rsquo;t relevant entities in my story, either, which gives me a little lee-way when it comes to that. This does go against D&amp;amp;D&amp;rsquo;s assumptions that gods exist and influence the world, I know, but bending those boundaries is just as enjoyable as staying within them.&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="elysium">Elysium&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I am going to write a separate article on my pantheon for Elysium, and what my train of thought was designing them. Hopefully you look forward to reading that!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing thoughts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Deities are great, y&amp;rsquo;all. They&amp;rsquo;re great ways to explain things in your world, from a planetary-scale to a small village&amp;rsquo;s culture. They&amp;rsquo;re also great vehicles for story arcs and adventures. While also keeping in mind that you don&amp;rsquo;t go overboard like I did, and keeping them relevant to the story to not overuse your creative juices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also my first article, so I would love to hear your thoughts about it in any way you can. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;m mostly just rambling about things and throwing some of my thoughts on it here and there, but that&amp;rsquo;s what this blog is for, right? I&amp;rsquo;m open to suggestions, criticism and discussion about the things I write. Thank you for reading, and I hope you look forward to my deep-dive into my deities for Elysium!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>