<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 12:01:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tabletopflore.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me and this blog</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/about/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 12:01:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/about/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;ve suddenly had the inspiration to start this blog. I want to use it to write down my thoughts and ideas about worldbuilding and different TTRPGs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="who-am-i">Who am I?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My name is Flore, a 22 year old man living in the Netherlands, who has been playing D&amp;amp;D for almost five years now. Most of that time has been as a DM. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Critical Role, which has been my main inspiration for being a DM and creating my own worlds. I used to study Aerospace Engineering, but I have switched over to Computer Science in 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-make-this-blog">Why make this blog?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time creating a lot of different worlds, like my dark and gloomy world of &lt;strong>Eden&lt;/strong>, and the much more fantastical world of &lt;strong>[[Halcyon]]&lt;/strong>. They are distinct in tone and execution, and I want to share the experiences I have had with creating and playing in those worlds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I could talk to my friends about any decisions and thoughts I have about these things. I can&amp;rsquo;t really write entire blog posts to my friends. They&amp;rsquo;re not &lt;em>that&lt;/em> engaged in my musings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some parts of this blog will be blocked out in white, only to be revealed when moused over. These blocks are parts of articles that I &lt;em>do&lt;/em> want to talk about but &lt;em>can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> for specific individuals, like my players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Test spoiler below.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="spoiler">So this is how a spoiler would look like in the blog. Don&amp;rsquo;t read it if its not for you.&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I hope some people can get enjoyment out of my ideas and thoughts, how bad or insignificant they might be. :)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>