<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 16:47:36 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Updated Site and Upcoming Content</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/updated-site-and-upcoming-content/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 16:47:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/updated-site-and-upcoming-content/</guid><description>As you can probably see from the website, I changed the look and feel of tabletopflore.com. I personally felt like it needed a bit of a makeover (even if it had a makeover relatively recently). I just like this look better for my blogging needs.
It is kind of funny to think that before this post I made two posts, both saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be back with new content soon!&amp;rdquo;, and then never making new content.</description></item><item><title>Long Awaited Update</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/long-awaited-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 21:38:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/long-awaited-update/</guid><description>It has been an absurdly long while since I posted anything on this site. Personally I&amp;rsquo;ve been very busy with my university study, next to writing and running my Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons 5e game that I&amp;rsquo;m playing with several of my IRL friends.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working more and more on the world of Ae&amp;rsquo;thar and it&amp;rsquo;s been really, really fun writing for it. I&amp;rsquo;m even slowly starting a different campaign based in a completely different portion of the world together with some friends on Discord.</description></item><item><title>Quick Little Update</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/quick-little-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/quick-little-update/</guid><description>Hey all! Quick little post here to let everyone that still reads this blog know that I&amp;rsquo;m working on a couple different articles right now. Most of them are about how I personally run games or prepare sessions, while others are more about some parts of worldbuilding I love fleshing out in my worlds. I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time lately working on Ae&amp;rsquo;thar, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a blast, but I will return to writing articles on this blog soon.</description></item><item><title>Pantheon of Ae'thar: More Deities, Story, and Culture</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-aethar-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-aethar-2/</guid><description>So, last post was quite a long one. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a great start to my pantheon already. This article will flesh out the pantheon more by adding minor deities to fill some domains, add the &amp;lsquo;one good story&amp;rsquo;, and develop how the culture and actual religion in this world would be like.
Even More Deities I looked at my current set of five deities and what domains they represent for clerics, and found out that we&amp;rsquo;re basically covering all of them (some even twice), besides Death, Grave, and Peace.</description></item><item><title>Pantheon of Ae'thar</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-aethar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheon-of-aethar/</guid><description>Like I said in my last article, this article is going to be me trying to take the (arguably small amount of) knowledge I gained from writing that article and apply that to my new world of Ae&amp;rsquo;thar. I want to see what kind of system I want to use and what I want to focus on, and maybe work out some cultures and religions as well. As not everyone knows what Ae&amp;rsquo;thar is, I&amp;rsquo;ll start by giving a small introduction to the world.</description></item><item><title>Pantheons and Religions</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheons-and-religions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/pantheons-and-religions/</guid><description>As the first article on this blog of mine, I wanted to discuss the role that the deities, religions, and pantheons in your world plays, both in worldbuilding and your tabletop games. I&amp;rsquo;m now figuring out the deities for my world of Ae&amp;rsquo;thar, and I wanted to share my thoughts about designing them in this article.
Worldbuilding Deities Personally, I use deities and pantheons because I really have to, most TTRPGs kind of expects you to have them in your world.</description></item><item><title>Start of a new Adventure</title><link>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/start-of-a-new-adventure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.tabletopflore.com/posts/start-of-a-new-adventure/</guid><description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;ve suddenly had the inspiration to start this blog. I want to use it to write down my thoughts and ideas about worldbuilding and different TTRPGs.
Who am I? My name is Flore, a 20 year old man living in the Netherlands, who has been playing D&amp;amp;D for almost four years now. Most of that time has been as a DM. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Critical Role, which has been my main inspiration for being a DM, and creating my own worlds.</description></item></channel></rss>