<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>religion on</title><link>/tags/religion/</link><description>Recent content in religion on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pantheon of Ae'thar: More Deities, Story, and Culture</title><link>/posts/pantheon-of-aethar-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pantheon-of-aethar-2/</guid><description>So, last post was quite a long one. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a great start to my pantheon already. This article will flesh out the pantheon more by adding minor deities to fill some domains, add the &amp;lsquo;one good story&amp;rsquo;, and develop how the culture and actual religion in this world would be like.
Even More Deities I looked at my current set of five deities and what domains they represent for clerics, and found out that we&amp;rsquo;re basically covering all of them (some even twice), besides Death, Grave, and Peace.</description></item><item><title>Pantheon of Ae'thar</title><link>/posts/pantheon-of-aethar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pantheon-of-aethar/</guid><description>Like I said in my last article, this article is going to be me trying to take the (arguably small amount of) knowledge I gained from writing that article and apply that to my new world of Ae&amp;rsquo;thar. I want to see what kind of system I want to use and what I want to focus on, and maybe work out some cultures and religions as well. As not everyone knows what Ae&amp;rsquo;thar is, I&amp;rsquo;ll start by giving a small introduction to the world.</description></item><item><title>Pantheons and Religions</title><link>/posts/pantheons-and-religions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pantheons-and-religions/</guid><description>As the first article on this blog of mine, I wanted to discuss the role that the deities, religions, and pantheons in your world plays, both in worldbuilding and your tabletop games. I&amp;rsquo;m now figuring out the deities for my world of Ae&amp;rsquo;thar, and I wanted to share my thoughts about designing them in this article.
Worldbuilding Deities Personally, I use deities and pantheons because I really have to, most TTRPGs kind of expects you to have them in your world.</description></item></channel></rss>